PHILIPP SCHULTE

1614 Hayes Street, San Francisco, CA 94117 | (C) 415-483-6781 | philipp.schulte@ymail.com

professional summary

Full-Stack JavaScript developer with almost 2 years of experience in developing scalable, maintainable, and secure Web applications. I love to build Single-Page Applications, breaking and fixing code, creating REST APIs and writing unit tests right from the start. I am a highly motivated and a hardworking individual with an insatiable appetite for learning.

skills

- HTML
- REACT
- NODE
- CHAI
- C

- CSS
- REDUX
- EXPRESS
- SINON
- ALGORITHMS

- JAVASCRIPT
- ANGULAR
- MONGODB
- MOCHA
- DATA STRUCTURES

work history

Instructor, DevMountain; Salt Lake City, Utah - May 2016-August 2016

I taught students fundamentals and additional tools of web development in 16-week intensive bootcamp. JavaScript was at the center of my teaching. My goal was to prepare my students for the work as junior web developers, so that they are able to change their career path by the end of the course. My day to day responsibilities included: lecturing on JavaScript fundamentals, libraries, and frameworks; preparing JavaScript code quizzes and training materials; design relevant, up-to-date curriculum for student instruction.

Front-End Developer, Novi Security; Orem, Utah - August 2015-May 2016

I worked on the Novi Mobile App. Novi is a battery-powered DIY security system which is armed and disarmed through the user's Novi mobile app. We developed a hybrid app using web technologies, while providing a native look and feel on each supported platform. My day to day responsibilities included: adding features; fixing bugs; writing unit tests; deploying the app to Apple App Store and Play Store.

Mentor, DevMountain; Provo, Utah – June 2015-August 2015

As a mentor, my first priority was the success of students attending DevMountain. My day to day responsibilities included: leading toy problems; leading daily group mini projects; lecturing on JavaScript fundamentals, libraries, and frameworks; writing curriculum; advising and pair programming with students on projects.

Structural Engineer, Leonhardt, Andrä und Partner; Berlin, Germany – February 2012-March 2015

I worked on design and production documents as well as construction specifications for various complex bridge projects. My day to day responsibilities included: programming the finite element method; analysis, design and plan production; construction site supervision.

education

University of Applied Sciences Potsdam, Germany – Bachelor's Degree in Civil Engineering, 2012 DevMountain, Provo, Utah – Web Dev Immersive Bootcamp, 2015